JEFF SHARP

Austin, TX

(512) 534-5477 jt74277@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jefftsharp/ Github: https://github.com/jt74277/Automated_Tests

SUMMARY

I am a well-organized and disciplined remote Quality Assurance test professional seeking a new opportunity to help raise the level of product and process quality within a small to medium sized company. Twelve years of experience in manual black box functional, exploratory, smoke, end-to-end, regression, acceptance, and usability testing on web and mobile apps, e-commerce modules, SAAS applications, and other types of software has given me a solid understanding of test frameworks, methodologies, and philosophies. I also have five years of test automation experience, both with codeless and coded tools. Most recently, I've been writing test automation in Ruby, rspec, and SitePrism in Capybara. The majority of my QA experience has been in an Agile SCRUM environment but I do have experience working in other environments, such as Waterfall and Kanban. The QA testing programs I've setup at multiple companies have all led to improvements in release processes and reductions in post-release bugs.

Relevant Technical Skills:

- Functional, exploratory, smoke, end-to-end, regression, and acceptance testing = 12 years
- Bug tracking (JIRA, Trac, Basecamp, Unfuddle, Phabricator, Trello) = 12 years
- Test script, test case, and test plan writing (TestRail, Confluence, Excel) = 10 years
- Test automation (Katalon Studio, Selenium, Ruby/rspec, Capybara) = 5 years
- REST API testing (Postman, Swagger) = 2 years
- Github = 3 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

7/2023 to 1/2024

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- Salesforce
- Ruby/rspec
- SitePrism
- AWS
- Selenium/Capybara
- Jenkins/circleci
- Github
- Trello
- API

3/2023 to 7/2023

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- Xcode
- Android Studio
- Github
- JIRA/Confluence
- API

6/2021 to 12/2022

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- Ruby/rspec
- Capybara
- SitePrism
- AWS
- Github
- circleci
- JIRA/Confluence
- API

BEYOND FINANCE Houston, TX/Chicago, IL - Remote

Sofware Developer in Test II (SDET II)

- Performed black box, functional, exploratory, and regression testing on internally developed custom Salesforce financial applications.
- Developed and maintained automated regression tests in rspec using Selenium and Capybara and managed releases with Github, AWS, and Jenkins.
- QA Lead for an Affordable Offer project which resulted in an over 50% improvement in Approval Rates for affordable offers and a 25% reduction in Average Handle Time.
- Wrote, updated, and managed test cases in Notion.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed deployments using Trello.
- Participated in all standup and planning ceremonies with the Engineering and Product teams I supported.
- Wrote and maintained process and support documentation in Notion/Google Sheets.

FAVOR DELIVERY Austin, TX - Remote

QA Analyst II

- Performed black box, functional, exploratory, and regression testing on internally developed native mobile apps using Kanban methodology.
- Wrote, updated, and managed test cases in TestRail.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed deployments using JIRA.
- Wrote and maintained process and support documentation and test plans in Confluence.
- Mentored junior QA Analysts.

DUTCHIE Bend, OR - Remote

QA Analyst II/QA Consultant

- Performed black box, API, functional, exploratory, integration, and regression testing on internally developed ecommerce and POS systems in multiple browsers on OS X in a Ruby on Rails/Javascript environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Wrote, updated, and managed test cases in TestRail.
- Developed and maintained automated regression tests in rspec using Selenium and Capybara and managed releases with Github and circleci.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed sprint deployments using JIRA.
- Trained software engineers on QA processes and testing procedures and consulted on test plans for new software feature releases.

3/2017 to 6/2021

Roger CPA Review/UWORLD Dallas, TX - Remote

Sr. QA Engineer

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- PHP
- Drupal
- Selenium IDE
- Katalon Studio
- JIRA/Confluence
- Salesforce
- Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation.
- Performed black box, API, functional, regression, and acceptance testing on internally developed
 websites and web apps in multiple browsers on OS X and Windows in a PHP/Drupal/Angular
 environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Wrote, administered, and executed automated pre and post deployment regression tests using Selenium IDE, Katalon Recorder, and Katalon Studio on a weekly basis.
- Led and directly managed a Jr. QA Engineer. Coordinated and led a team of 4 QA Analysts/Engineers.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed sprint deployments using JIRA.
- Assisted with JIRA administration duties.
- Wrote and maintained documentation in Confluence.

11/2016 to 11/2018

- Trello

SNAPISOFT Boulder, CO - Remote

QA Lead, part time freelance contractor

documentation in Confluence.

- ◆ Relevant Technology:

 ◆ Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated
 - Performed black box, API, functional, regression, acceptance, and usability testing on internally developed websites in multiple versions of multiple browsers on OS X and Windows.
 - Wrote functional specifications and requirements for development projects.
 - Developed test plans and detailed test cases and tracked bugs and defects using Trello.

7/2016 to 3/2017

CLEAN ENERGY COLLECTIVE Louisville, CO - On-site

QA Analyst

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- Selenium
- JIRA/Confluence
- Performed manual and automated functional, acceptance, and regression testing of back office web applications in a PHP/.NET environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Administered and executed automated regression tests in a Selenium environment.
- Tested and verified sprint code deployments in multiple operating environments.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed sprint deployments using JIRA.
- Responsible for the administration of all aspects of the organizational JIRA environment, including developing workflows and schemes, implementing suggested screen/field changes, and managing the various projects and user permissions and security.

8/2013 to 9/2017

♦ Relevant Technology:– Phabricator

BURLY HOUSE NETWORKS Austin, TX - Remote

QA Lead, part time freelance contractor

- Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation.
- Performed black box, API, functional, system, end-to-end, regression, acceptance, and usability testing on internally developed websites in multiple versions of multiple browsers.
- Wrote functional specifications, requirements for development projects, and detailed test cases.
- Tracked bugs and defects using Phabricator.
- Trained and managed a second QA Analyst and coordinated and managed their responsibilities.

3/2013 to 3/2016 \$58,000/year

ACCELLA, Baltimore, MD (Telecommuting from Lubbock, TX)

QA Lead

- Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation.
- Performed black box, API, functional, system, end-to-end, regression, acceptance, load, and usability testing on mobile applications and internally developed websites.
- Manual testing of mobile apps on Android and iOS devices, including phones and tablets.
- Manual testing of websites in multiple versions of multiple browsers on OS X and various versions of Windows using VirtualBox VM's.
- Wrote functional specifications and requirements for development projects.
- Developed test plans and detailed test cases.
- Tracked bugs and defects using Unfuddle.

EDUCATION

Abilene Christian University, Abilene, TX BBA in Information Systems 3.2/4.0

Oklahoma City University, Tulsa, OK MBA in General Business 4.0/4.0